Where do those scars lie within your chest?
sono kizu wa mune no doko ni arimasu ka?
Can you hear my voice somewhere inside your heart?
kono koe wa kokoro no dokoka de kikoeteimasu ka?
When your scars and mine join together...
sono kizu to kono kizu wo kasaneta nara
When my voice and yours resound together...
kono koe to sono koe wo hibikaseta nara
Our intensity, hot tears, and bashful smiles...
hageshisa atsui namida hazukashisou na hohoemi
I used to think nothing of them, but now,
anna ni mo nanimo nai tte omoeteta watashi kara
So many unstoppable feelings are overflowing!
afuredasu yo konna ni mo tomedo nai kanjou ga ima
You're the one who finds yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo mitsukedasu
You're the one who saves yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo sukuidasu
So much is wrong and everyone breaks into a run.
machigai darake de daremo ga hashiridasu
You're the one who lives your own life,
kimi ga kimi wo ikite yuku
Trembling, hesitating all the while
furue nagara, tomadoi nagara
In a world where you're never truly alone.
hitori kiri janai sekai
But you're the only one of you there is!
dakedo kimi wa tatta ichi nin kimi shika inai
This is bad!
こりゃ ヤバいぜ！
It's spewing fire!
（トーリー）火を吐いた！
I'd heard their fire-related organs had become vestigial!
関連器官は退化したって聞いたぞ！
Elias...
（チセ）エリアス！
It's an atavism.
（エリアス）先祖返りだな
It's become like the dragons
you'd read about in fairy tales.
まさしく
おとぎ話のドラゴンってわけだ
Elias, he can still go home.
エリアス！ あの子は まだ帰れます
帰りたがってます！
He wants to go home!
帰る場所があります！
He has a place to go home to!
Please, teach me how to help.
やり方を教えてください
Your selfish requests are never for yourself.
（エリアス）
君のわがままは
いつも 君自身のためじゃないな
It's all right.
大丈夫
That's why I'm here to begin with.
元から そのために ここにいるのさ
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
（エリアス）
まずは ドラゴンに触れるんだ
First, touch the dragon.
That way, you can absorb its magic.
そうすれば
ドラゴンの魔力を吸い取れるはずだ
そして それを僕が吸い取る
And I'll absorb that before your body breaks.
君の体が壊れる前に
Okay.
はい
Alice!
（レンフレッド）アリス！
（アリス）はい！
Right!
We're going to draw the dragon's attention.
あたしたちが
ドラゴンの気を引き付ける
Thanks.
（チセ）ありがとう！
（レンフレッド）こっちだ！
Over here!
（アリス）この〜！
Take this!
This way!
（アドルフ）ほら こっちだ！
Fire!
（２人）火だ！
（セルキー）えい！
（アドルフ）メリトゥーリ！
（アリス）あっ…
Merituuli!
You naughty boy!
（セルキー）悪い子ですね！
We're going back home!
早く おうちに帰るですよ〜！
（チセ）今！
Now!
Here we go.
（エリアス）行くよ
（チセ）へっ？
By the base of its neck.
（エリアス）
首元だ　力の太い流れがある
There's a powerful flow there.
（チセ）うわっ！
（アリス）チセ！
Chise!
It's trying to go outside!
（トーリー）外に出る気か？
Merituuli, distract it!
メリトゥーリ！ 目くらましを！
Gah, jeez!
ああん もう！
いけない！
This is bad!
It's going to cave!
（レンフレッド）崩れるぞ！
（エリアス）チセ！
Chise!
（ルツ）チセ！
Damn it! Be careful!
（ルツ）たく… むちゃするな！
（チセ）ルツ！
Ruth.
Chise, are you ready?
（エリアス）チセ 準備はいい？
Elias!
（チセ）エリアス！
Ruth!
（チセ）ルツ！
（ルツ）ああ！
Right.
（女性）あら？
Huh?
The moon looks odd.
変な月
Chise, are you all right?
（ルツ）
チセ 大丈夫か？
Ruth, how's Elias?
（チセ）
ルツ！ エリアスは？
Singed, but he's fine.
（ルツ）
焦げたけど 無事だ
今 行く！
We're on our way.
The river.
（チセ）川だ
（ルツ）
おい チセ！
Wait, Chise...
You don't have to come with me, Ruth.
ルツ 来なくていいから
みんなを連れて 迎えに来て
Go get the others and then come get me.
Chise, you better not be...
（ルツ）
チセ？ お前 まさか…
（チセ）大丈夫
It's okay.
Let's go home together.
一緒に帰ろう
バカ！
Idiot!
Chise!
（エリアス）チセ！
Hey, hang in there!
（レンフレッド）
おい しっかりしろ
Ruth...
（エリアス）ルツ… チセは？
Where's Chise?
To think it escaped...
（カルタフィルス）
まさか 逃げるなんて…
Shannon-san...
シャノンさ…
なん…
Why...
How do you feel?
（シャノン）大丈夫？ 起きれる？
Can you get up?
I'll get up.
（チセ）起き… ます
Wow.
わお…
きついかもしれないけど
外さないでね
It might be tight, but don't take it off.
It feels like it's going to burst.
（チセ）なんか 破裂しそうです
Chise!
（エリアス）チ…
（アンジェリカ）チセ！
Angelica-san.
アンジェリカさ…
（ヒューゴ）ひっでえ臭いだなあ！
Jeez, you reek.
（シャノン）
先を越されてるヘタレ
She beat you to her, loser.
I'd do the same to my own daughter.
自分の娘でも 同じようにするよ
I told you not to try to do everything by yourself.
１人で何でもやろうとするなって
言っただろ
こいつには
さんざん 言い聞かせてやったから
I already gave him an earful.
I wonder what she did to him.
（チセ）
何されたんだろ…
How's the dragon?
（チセ）ドラゴンは…
And the other people?
ほかの人たち… は？
Everyone went home.
（エリアス）みんな 戻ったよ
ドラゴンは夢の中だ
The dragon is sleeping.
Thank goodness.
よかった
Elias, are you burned or anything?
エリアス
やけどとか… ないですか？
（エリアス）
僕より君のほうが大ごとなの
分かってないだろう
You don't realize you're in
worse shape than I am, do you?
実は あんまり
Actually, not really.
（エリアス）知ってる
I know.
Well now, I can't let that lousy explainer explain, can I?
（リンデル）
さて…
説明べたに
説明させるわけにはいかんの
Lindel-san.
リンデルさん
Your arm...
その腕…
損な役回りを引き受けさせた
I've forced you into an unenviable role.
すまない
I'm sorry.
I only did it because I could.
できてしまったから
やっただけです
That's why this is so bad.
（リンデル）だから マズい
おぬしは
ドラゴンの力に呪われておる
You've been cursed by the dragon's powers.
Cursed?
（チセ）呪い？
（リンデル）
それは おぬしの体を蝕(むしば)む
It's going to fester in your body.
It'll attack, torment, and hex you.
責め苛(さいな)み 呪う
人の体では 到底 抑えきれぬ
No human body could contain it.
遅かれ早かれ 身が壊れるだろう
Sooner or later, your body will fall apart.
How long will this body last?
この体は どれくらい もちますか？
すまんが 分からんのだ
I don't know. I'm sorry.
I see.
そうですか…
あ〜 その…
So...
I've lived with two curses so far.
私は 今まで
２つの呪いと一緒に生きて…
生きてきてしまって
I was forced to live with them.
One is this, my Sleigh Beggy body.
１つは
夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)としての この体で
もう１つは…
The other...
As long as I live, it'll probably never leave me.
私が生きるかぎり
多分
ずっと離れることのない呪いです
Taking on one more doesn't seem like such a big deal.
今更 １つ増えたところで
どうってことないですよ
You're...
（エリアス）君は…
He's angry.
怒った
Huh? That's him angry?
（アンジェリカ）
え… あれ 怒ったの？
I'm sorry.
すまない　許せとは言えぬ
I can't ask you to forgive me.
Please don't apologize.
（チセ）
謝らないでください
This is proof.
これは証明なんです
That I was able to think of someone other than myself.
私が 自分じゃない誰かのことを…
考えることができたんだっていう
You do have the option of living on the other side.
（シャノン）
あなたが あちらへ住むという
手もあるけど
But that's...
（アンジェリカ）でも それは…
（チセ）考えてみます
I'll think about it.
（アンジェリカ）チセ！
Chise!
（シャノン）いいの？
Are you sure?
You may cease to be human.
人でなくなってしまう
かもしれないのよ？
（チセ）腹は くくったんです
I'm ready for the worst.
I have to do what I can.
なりふり構っていられません
Are you sure you should be out?
（ルツ）
出てきて 大丈夫だったのか？
しかも 黙って
You didn't tell anyone, either.
I prefer the air outside.
外の空気のほうが好き
How can you be smiling?
（ルツ）なんで… 笑える？
When did you...
どこから？
Since you tried to leave from the
window and flipped around in the sky.
（エリアス）
君が窓から出ようとして
空中で１回転したところから
That's from the very beginning.
（チセ）最初からじゃないですか
My puppy seems to have lost her mind.
（エリアス）
僕の子犬(パピー)はバカになったらしい
I was just pretending to be smart.
（チセ）
物分かりのいいふりを
してただけです
Haven't I told you?
前に言いませんでした？
You've forgotten to let me know when
you go out, yet you're still well-spoken.
（エリアス）
僕に声をかけることも忘れたのに
口は回る？
I mean, you didn't reply to me.
（チセ）
だって
返事しなかったじゃないですか
（エリアス）整理してた
I was straightening things out.
（チセ）一日かけて？
All day?
（エリアス）そう
Yeah.
You always try to go somewhere by yourself.
君は いつも１人で
どこかへ行こうとする
君は…
Even though you always
offer me your hand and grip back.
いつだって
僕に手を差し出して
握り返すくせに
Even though you ask me to come home.
帰ろうって誘うくせに
それなのに
こんなにあっけなく
And yet you're going to leave me, just like that?
僕を
置いていこうとするのか
It's not like I'm going to die right away.
（チセ）
すぐに死ぬわけじゃないですよ
きっと
I don't think.
How was I so optimistic?
（エリアス）
どうして 楽観視できたんだろう
I knew this would happen to you someday.
僕は君が いつかこうなるって
知ってたはずなのに
I should have stopped you, but I didn't.
君を止めるべきなのに
そうしなかった
僕は どこかで 今でも まだ
Somewhere inside,
I'm still thinking that you're always
going to be in that home, going forward.
君が ずっと あの家にいて
これからも いるんだって思ってる
That you would manage somehow.
君なら きっと大丈夫だって
It's funny.
（チセ）おかしいですね
（エリアス）何？
What is?
At first, we were only using each other.
（チセ）
最初は お互い
利用してただけだったのに
I never thought this would
happen just because we were together.
一緒にいるだけで
こんなことになるなんて
私は… 生きたくないと
思ってました
Before this, I was sure I didn't want to live.
But so many people helped me,
でも いろんな人が
助けてくれて
私なんかにも お礼を
言われるようなことが
and I found out that even I could do
things that are worth being thanked for.
できるんだって分かって
I'm not just waiting for
someone to tell me I'm welcome to stay.
いてもいいって言われるのを
待ってるんじゃなくて
I started wanting to stay and wanting to do something.
ここにいて何かしたいって
思えるようになって
Self-sacrifice.
（エリアス）自己犠牲を…
You think that by destroying
yourself, you can earn the right to be here.
自分を壊すことで
ここにいる資格を得られると
考えている？
E-Elias...
（ルツ）エ… エリアス
どうなんでしょう
I wonder.
分からないです
I don't know.
I only did what I did because I could.
今回のは やれたから
やっただけで…
I'm not lying, it's just that there are some things
うそではなく
人間には 自分でも
よく分からないことがあるんです
about humans that we don't understand ourselves.
（エリアス）え… そうなの？
Really?
それに
あなたのパピーはバカですから
Besides, your puppy is a stupid one.
Her body seems to act before her mind thinks.
体のほうが
先に動いちゃうみたいなんです
エリアス…
Elias, will you help this idiot think of a way
バカな私と一緒に
考えてくれますか？
that the two of us can stay next to each other?
私とエリアスが
隣にいられるやり方を
I don't have the same ability to take action that you do.
（エリアス）
僕は君ほど
パッと走りだせない
でも 君と一緒に
But, I can go find out with you.
確かめに行くことは
できる
Please take me with you.
ちゃんと
僕を連れていってよ
We have to find it.
（チセ）
見つけなきゃ
考えなきゃ…
We have to think
of a way to move forward.
前に進むためのやり方を
Hello.
（マリエル）こんにちは
（マリエル）私はマリエル
I'm Mariel.
山羊(やぎ)飼いのマリエル
Goatherder Mariel.
I'm what they call a witch.
魔女ってものをやってるわ
（エリアス）競売場で取り引き？
A transaction at the auction?
Yup.
（マリエル）
そう
私のお金をあげる代わりに
I asked for the dragon's blood in exchange for money.
ドラゴンの血を頂戴って
お願いしてたんだけど…
It doesn't look like that'll work.
無理そうね
（チセ）ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
You... Your arm...
あなた それ…
ちょっと見るだけよ
過保護ね
I'm just going to take a look.
You're so overprotective.
Mariel-san...
マリエルさ…
Ouch.
光輝く地の雌神(めがみ)
Gleaming goddess of the land,
蛇裂きし 嵐の雄神(おがみ)
snake-shredding god of storms...
Lend us your hand,
your eyes, for the batting of an eyelid.
その御手(みて)を その玉の眼(め)を
またたきの間 お貸しください
What is this thing?
なあに これ！
すっごい怖い！
It's so creepy!
A dragon's curse?
ドラゴンの呪いね
Say, do you have any interest in becoming a witch?
ねえ？
あなた 魔女になる気はない？
Witches specialize in curses.
呪いは魔女の専門なの
私たちの仲間… カヴンに入れば
If you become one of us—if you join
our coven—we might be able to help you.
みんなで あなたを
何とかしてあげられるかも
（エリアス）ダメだ
No.
Do you really have the confidence to
tell a woman what to do with her life?
（マリエル）
あなたに 女の人生を
指図できる自信があって？
（チセ）マリエルさん
Mariel-san, what do I need to do to become one of you?
仲間になるために
私は
何をしなければなりませんか？
（エリアス）チセ
Chise.
For starters, join our gathering as a guest.
とりあえず
お客人として集会に来て
Soon, if you can.
できれば 早めに
Open that when you're ready.
（マリエル）
決心がついたら 開けてね
お返事 待ってるわ
I'll be awaiting your reply.
Goodbye.
（チセ）さよなら
Hello.
（マリエル）こんにちは
（ステラ）こんにちは
Unbelievable.
（マリエル）
やあねえ あんな小さい子に
Such a young girl?
（ステラ）はい これ！
Here you go.
A card?
（チセ）カード？
It's an invitation to my birthday party.
（ステラ）
私の誕生日パーティーの招待状
チセは いつなの？
When's yours, Chise?
（チセ）あ… 今日
Today.
（ステラ）
今日？ なんで？ パーティーは？
Today?
What?! Where's your party?!
どうして やってあげないのよ！
Why aren't you holding a party for her?
Par... tay?
（エリアス）ぱあ… てい？
う〜 もう…
Jeez.
Okay, next year.
じゃあ 来年！
何やるか 考えておくのよ
You better come up with some plans.
うん らいね…
Next year...
What's wrong?
（ステラ）どうしたの？
I feel nauseous all of a sudden.
（チセ）急に 吐き気が…
I'm going to the washroom, so...
お手洗い 行くから 先に…
It's okay, I just came to give you the card.
（ステラ）
ううん
カードを渡しに来ただけだから
Take care.
お大事にね
（エリアス）チセ
Chise...
（チセ）ゴホッ ゴホッ…
やっと 死にたくないって
思えた端から これですよ
All this, just as I'd decided I don't want to die.
Let's join the witch's gathering.
（エリアス）魔女の集会に出よう
いいんですか？
You're okay with that?
あなたのお弟子さん
春を越せないかもしれないわ
Your apprentice might not make it through the spring.
（エリアス）いいんだ
It's fine.
君の体を どうにかするほうが先だ
What matters more is to take care of your health.
Thank you.
（チセ）ありがとう… ございます
I have to think about my party next year.
来年のパーティーのこと
考えなきゃですもんね
（カルタフィルス）
ふ〜ん ドラゴンの呪いか
A dragon's curse, huh?
死ねない僕の呪いと
死に至る お前の呪い
Between my curse keeping me from
dying, and your curse leading you to death...
Things might work out pretty well.
意外と相性がいいかもしれないよ
The moon witnessed our incomplete cycles.
tsuki wa miteita kaketeru bokura
We called to one another,
tagai wo yobiai nagara
Walking distant paths as we took the long way around.
toomawari de tooi michi wo aruita
Red and black attract one another...
hikiyoseau aka to kuro ga
Shadow and light chase after one another...
oikakeau yami to hikari ga
They're made of two related things
futatsu no tsuranaru mono de tsukurareteru yo
...everything in this world is.
konoyo no subete wa
Because you're here, I'm here.
anata ga iru kara watashi wa iru
Even apart, we're side by side.
hanaretemo soba ni iru
soba ni iru
We're side by side.
Everyone is continually searching
daremo ga jibun no mou hitotsu no
For one precious thing
kataware to iu taisetsu na mono
That they can call their other half.
sagashi tsudzuketeru yo
The reality presented at the
witches' gathering was a cruel one.
（チセ）
魔女の集会で突きつけられたのは
残酷な現実だった
The mage sets out to save the girl, but...
少女を救うため
魔法使いは動きだすが…
The only thing that can replace a life is another life.
（マリエル）
命の代わりにするものは
命しかないわよ